SUK YEE YONG

CSIRO Space and Astronomy Corner Vimiera and Pembroke Roads Marsfield, NSW 2122, Australia

+61 (0)2 9372 4289

⋈ sukyee.yong@csiro.au

https://yongsukyee.github.io

Profile Summary

I am a Space and Astronomy CSIRO Early Research Career (CERC) Postdoctoral Fellow in the Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence Future Science Platform (MLAI FSP). My project involves developing ML and AI techniques for finding the rare and unknowns in astronomical datasets.

WORK EXPERIENCE

09/2020-present

CERC Postdoctoral Fellowship in MLAI FSP, Space and Astronomy, CSIRO

* Supervisor: Dr. George Hobbs

* Project: Finding the unknowns in radio astronomy data sets

03/2020 - 08/2020

Postdoctoral Research Fellow in Astrophysics, School of Physics, University of Melbourne

* Supervisor: Prof. Rachel Webster

* Project: Quasar disk-wind phenomenology

10/2019 - 03/2020

Research Data Engineer via Australian Postgraduate Research (APR) Intern, Centre for Eye Research Australia (CERA) Limited, Royal Victorian Eye and Ear Hospital

- ★ Supervisors: Dr. Xavier Hadoux (industry), Prof. Rachel Webster (academic)
- \star Project title: The eyes and the sky medical image analysis with astrophysics supercomputing

07/2019 - 09/2019

Astrophysics Intern via Internship Program 2019, Astronomy and Data Computing Services (ADACS), Swinburne University of Technology

- * Supervisors: Dr. Robert Bassett, Dr. Gregory Poole; Line manager: Prof. Jarrod Hurley
- * Project title: Recover the 3D shape of galaxy using deep learning

EDUCATION

11/2019-03/2020

Specialist Certificate in Research Practice for Scientists

The University of Melbourne, Parkville, VIC, Australia Science Research Internship at the Centre for Eye Research Australia

03/2016-02/2020 PhD-Science (Physics) The University of Melbourne, Parkville, VIC, Australia Thesis title: Nature of Quasar Disk-wind Supervisor: Prof. Rachel Webster; Co-supervisor: Dr. Anthea King 07/2013 - 07/2015Master of Science (Physics) with Distinction The University of Melbourne, Parkville, VIC, Australia Thesis title: Quasar Disk Wind Models and Emission Line Profiles Supervisor: Prof. Rachel Webster Weighted average mark (WAM): 82.125/100.0 07/2010 - 12/2012Bachelor of Science (Physics) with Distinction The Pennsylvania State University, University Park, PA, United States Major in Physics with Distinction and minor in Mathematics Grade point average (GPA): 3.85/4.0

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

12/2013-02/2020	Postgraduate Student, School of Physics, University of Melbourne * PhD-Science (Physics) research project * Master of Science (Physics) research project
07/2015– $02/2016$	Research Assistant, School of Physics, University of Melbourne * Supervisor: Prof. Rachel Webster
08/2012 – 11/2012	Research Assistant, Physics Department, Pennsylvania State University * Supervisor: Dr. Stephane Coutu
05/2012 – 08/2012	Research for Undergraduate Experience (REU) Internship, Physics Department, Pennsylvania State University * Supervisor: Dr. Stephane Coutu
05/2011– $08/2011$	Research Assistant, Astronomy and Astrophysics Department, Pennsylva- nia State University * Supervisor: Prof. David Burrows

TEACHING AND SUPERVISING EXPERIENCES

07/2013 – 12/2020	Laboratory Demonstrator, School of Physics, University of Melbourne
03 – 06/2019	Teaching Assistant, School of Physics, University of Melbourne
2016 – 2017	Co-Supervising Undergraduate Student for SCIE30001, School of
	Physics, University of Melbourne

PUBLICATIONS

2020	Yong, Suk Yee, Webster, R. L., King, A. L., Bate, N. F., Labrie, K.,
	and O'Dowd, M. J. (2020). Determining quasar orientation. MNRAS,
	491(1):1320–1334 [ADS arXiv]
2019	S. Y. Yong and Webster, R. L. (2019). Black hole mass estimation: Mod-
	elling the biases. In 2019 6th International Conference on Space Science and
	Communication (IconSpace), pages 139–143 [IEEE]

Moustakas, L., Anguita, T., Chartas, G., Cornachione, M., Dai, X., Fian, C.,
Jimenez-Vicente, J., Labrie, K., Macleod, C., Mediavilla, E., Morgan, C. W.,
O'Dowd, M., Lewis, G., Motta, V., Nierenberg, A., Pooley, D., Rojas, K.,
Sluse, D., Vernardos, G., Webster, R., and Yong, Suk Yee (2019). Quasar microlensing: Revolutionizing our understanding of quasar structure and dynamics. BAAS, 51(3):487 [ADS]

- Bate, N. F., Vernardos, G., O'Dowd, M. J., Neri-Larios, D. M., Webster, R. L., Floyd, D. J. E., Barone-Nugent, R. L., Labrie, K., King, A. L., and Yong, S.-Y. (2018). HST imaging of four gravitationally lensed quasars. MNRAS, 479:4796–4814 [ADS | arXiv]
- 2018 Yong, S. Y., King, A. L., Webster, R. L., Bate, N. F., O'Dowd, M. J., and Labrie, K. (2018). Using the Properties of Broad Absorption Line Quasars to Illuminate Quasar Structure. *MNRAS*, 479:4153–4171 [ADS | arXiv]
- O'Dowd, M., Bate, N. F., Webster, R. L., Labrie, K., King, A. L., and Yong,
 S. Y. (2018). The intrinsic far-UV spectrum of the high-redshift quasar
 B1422+231. MNRAS, 473:4722-4730 [ADS | arXiv]
- 2017 Yong, S. Y., Webster, R. L., King, A. L., Bate, N. F., O'Dowd, M. J., and Labrie, K. (2017). The Kinematics of Quasar Broad Emission Line Regions Using a Disk-Wind Model. *PASA*, 34:e042 [ADS | arXiv]
- 2016 **Yong, S. Y.**, Webster, R. L., and King, A. L. (2016). Black Hole Mass Estimation: How Good is the Virial Estimate? *PASA*, 33:e009 [ADS | arXiv]

AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

2021	3 rd prize in postdoc pitch, Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence
	Reimagining Science 2021
2016 – 2020	Melbourne Research Scholarship, University of Melbourne
2019	Best paper award, 6 th International Conference on Space Science and Com-
	munication
2018	Science Abroad Travelling Scholarship, University of Melbourne
2015	Ramm Prize in Experimental Physics, University of Melbourne
2014	Coursework Studentship, University of Melbourne
2012	Donald and Barbara Weyenberg Graduate Fellowship, Pennsylvania State
	University
2011 – 2012	Bert Elsbach Scholarship in Physics, Pennsylvania State University
2010 – 2012	Dean's List for every semester, Pennsylvania State University
2008 – 2012	Public Service Department Scholarship for Overseas Degree Programme,
	Malaysia

SEMINARS, COLLOQUIA, AND INVITED TALKS

03/2021	* Talk: Hunting for the Unknowns in the Universe
03/2021	Object Detection Forum, CSIRO MLAI FSP, Virtual ★ Talk: Hunting the Unknown in the Universe(s)
09/2020	Managing Your Career during a Pandemic, Astronomical Society of Australia Early Career Researcher Chapter, Virtual * Panelist: Discussed and shared my personal journey in data science job
06/2019	PhD Completion Seminar, University of Melbourne, VIC, Australia ⋆ Talk: Kinematical Disk-wind Model of Quasars

07/2018 | Research Visitor, University of Southampton, Winchester, United Kingdom

★ Talk: Quasar Disk Winds

08/2017 | Geoff Opat Seminar Series, University of Melbourne, VIC, Australia

★ Talk: Modelling Quasar Broad Emission Line Regions

CONFERENCE CONTRIBUTIONS

Collaborative Conference on Computational and Data Intensive Science C3DIS, Virtual
\star Lightning talk: Hunting the Unknowns in Murriyang, an Anomaly De-
tection Approach Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence Reimagining Science
2021, Virtual
* Subcommittee
* Postdoc pitch Australia-ChinA ConsortiuM for Astrophysical Research Virtual
Workshop, Virtual
\star Lead technical supporter
European Astronomical Society Annual Meeting 2020, Virtual * ePoster: A Proxy for Quasar Orientation in the Ultraviolet/Optical
X-Sensing 2019 Cross-disciplinary Conference on Scientific Analytics, Coffs Harbour, NSW, Australia
* Hack day: Automated mapping of mangrove and saltmarsh from aerial imagery
2019 6 th International Conference on Space Science and Commu-
nication, Pulai Springs Resort, Johor, Malaysia
 ★ Talk and paper: Black Hole Mass Estimation: Modelling the Biases ★ Best paper award in track Astronomy and Astrophysics, Interdisciplinary
Space Science and Others
Astronomical Society of Australia Annual Scientific Meeting 2019, University of Queensland, QLD, Australia
\star Talk: Orientation Tracer of Quasars in the UV/Optical
Research Bazaar, University of Melbourne, VIC, Australia
★ Helper: Python★ Poster: Digital research tools used
Manhattan Microlensing 2019, Center for Computational Astrophysics,
NY, United States
* Talk: Searching for Quasar Orientation in the UV/Optical PhD Summer School: Supermassive Pholes and their Heat
PhD Summer School: Supermassive Black Holes and their Host Galaxies, Asiago Astrophysical Observatory, Asiago, Italy
* Talk: An Update on Black Hole Mass Estimation: How good is the virial
estimate? Astronomical Society of Australia Annual Scientific Meeting 2018,
Swinburne University of Technology, VIC, Australia
* Talk: Infer Structure of Quasar with Machine Learning
Research Bazaar, University of Melbourne, VIC, Australia * Helper: Python
★ Poster: Digital research tools used

 $Suk\ Yee\ Yong @csiro.au$

07/2017	Astronomical Society of Australia Annual Scientific Meeting 2017, Australian National University, ACT, Australia * Talk: Using Broad Absorption Lines to Illuminate Quasar Structure * Workshop: ADACS Introduction to Machine Learning
06/2017	AMSI Winter School 2017 on Computational Foundations of Data Science, Queensland University of Technology, QLD, Australia * Talk: Kinematical Model of the Quasar Broad Emission Line Region
05/2017	Manhattan Microlensing 2017, American Museum of Natural History, NY, United States ★ Talk: Modelling the Kinematics of Quasar Disk-winds
02/2017	Research Bazaar, University of Melbourne, VIC, Australia ★ Helper: Python ★ Poster: Digital research tools used
07/2016	From theory to applications: celebrating a century of gravitational lensing, Universiteit Leiden, Leiden, Netherlands * Poster: Single Object Weak Lensing
04/2016	SciCoder 7 Workshop 2016, University of Melbourne, VIC, Australia * Local organising committee
02/2016	Research Bazaar: Visualising Data on the Web using D3, University of Melbourne, VIC, Australia * Helper: D3 Stream * Poster: Digital research tools used
09/2015	TORUS 2015, University of Southampton, Winchester, United Kingdom ★ Poster: Black Hole Mass Estimation: How good is the virial estimate?
11/2014	Mount Stromlo Christmas Seminar, Mount Stromlo Observatory, ACT, Australia ★ Talk: Exploring the Broad Line Region

SELECTED CONFERENCES AND WORKSHOPS ATTENDED

12/2020	34 th Neural Information Processing Systems 2020, Virtual
12/2020	15 th Asian Conference on Computer Vision, Virtual
09/2020	2020 30 th IEEE International Workshop on Machine Learning for
	Signal Processing, Virtual
09/2020	The Future of Meetings Symposium, Virtual
07/2020	NVIDIA Accelerated Computing Workshop Australia & New
	Zealand, Virtual
07/2020	Astronomical Society of Australia Annual Scientific Meeting 2020,
	Virtual
07/2020	Harley Wood School of Astronomy, Virtual
11/2018	SciCoder Workshop 2018, University of Melbourne, VIC, Australia
11/2018	Biarri Applied Mathematics Conference 2018, RMIT University, VIC,
	Australia
07/2017	Tech Savvy Astronomer Workshop, University of Melbourne, VIC, Aus-
	tralia
11/2015	.Astronomy 7, University of Sydney and Justice & Police Museum, NSW,
	Australia
04/2015	OzSKA: radio astronomy in the next decade, University of Melbourne,
	VIC, Australia

02/2015	Astroinformatics Summer School, Australian National University, ACT,
	Australia
07/2014	Astronomical Society of Australia Annual Scientific Meeting, Mac-
	quarie University, NSW, Australia
04/2014	AusGO/AAO Observational Technical Workshop, AAO Headquarters,
•	NSW. Australia

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE AND MEMBERSHIPS

Journal referee Duty astronomer Member Publications of the Astronomical Society of Australia (PASA)

Australia Telescope Compact Array (ATCA)

Sigma Pi Sigma National Physics Honor Society

PUBLIC OUTREACH AND INVOLVEMENT

06/2021–Present	PULsar Student Exploration online at Parkes (PULSE@Parkes), CSIRO Aus-
	tralia Telescope National Facility
10/2018 – 12/2019	Interferometer Project, University of Melbourne
02/2018 – 12/2019	Research Platform Services Python Team Lead, University of Melbourne
08/2016 – 12/2019	Telescopes in Schools, University of Melbourne
08/2014 – 08/2019	University Open Day, University of Melbourne
04/2019	Women in Physics Camp, Queenscliff
07/2018	Girls in Physics Day, University of Melbourne
05/2018	Stargazing Live Guinness World Record, University of Melbourne
07/2016 – 12/2017	Bike Co-op, University of Melbourne
09/2016	Astronomy and Light Festival, Scienceworks
06/2016	Astrophysics Work Experience, University of Melbourne
08/2015	Astronomy and Light Festival, Scienceworks
08/2015	Science Festival, University of Melbourne
10/2014	Women in Physics Camp, Mount Buller
07/2012	Art Fest Science Outreach, Pennsylvania State University

SKILLS

Languages | English, Malay (fluent); Chinese, Japanese (basic) Programming | Python (fluent); C++ (basic)

INTERESTS

Musical Piano, guitar Sport and fitness Boxing, muay thai, cycling

REFERENCES

Dr. George
Hobbs
CSIRO Space and Astronomy, Marsfield, NSW 2122, Australia
Webster

CSIRO Space and Astronomy, Marsfield, NSW 2122, Australia

George hobbs@csiro.au

School of Physics, University of Melbourne, Parkville, VIC 3010, Australia

Prof. Rachel
Webster

Prof. Rachel
Webster

Prof. Rachel
Webster

School of Physics, University of Melbourne, Parkville, VIC 3010, Australia

Prof. Rachel
Webster

Prof. Rachel

A/Prof Peter van Wijngaarden

Centre for Eye Research Australia, Royal Victorian Eye and Ear Hospital, East Melbourne, VIC 3002, Australia

(a) +61 (0)3 9929 8429

⊠ peterv@unimelb.edu.au

Dr. Xavier Hadoux Centre for Eye Research Australia, Royal Victorian Eye and Ear Hospital, East Melbourne, VIC 3002, Australia

9 +61 (0)3 9929 8368

⊠ xavier.hadoux@unimelb.edu.au

Dr. Robert Bassett Centre for Astrophysics and Supercomputing, Swinburne University of Technology, Hawthorn, VIC 3122, Australia

9 +61 (0)3 9214 5706

⊠ rbassett@swin.edu.au